Now, to put our new knowledge into practice and
では新しい知識を実践して
use Neural Networks in TensorFlow to build an ML model.
TensorFlowでNNを使い MLモデルを構築します
It's time for another exciting lab using Neural Networks to build ML model.
NNを使ってMLモデルを構築する 新しいラボを始めます
In this lab, you will use the canned estimator,
このラボでは準備済みのEstimator
DNNReggressor class in TensorFlow to
DNNReggressorクラスを TensorFlowで使用して
predict median housing price based on many different features.
多数の特徴を基に住宅費の平均値を予測します
The data is based on a 1990 census data from California.
データは国勢調査データに基づいています
This data is at the city block level,
このデータは街区レベルなので
so these features reflect the total number of rooms in that block,
特徴はその街区の総部屋数や
or the total number of people who live on that block, respectively. Welcome back.
その街区の総住居者数を表します コードに戻ります
We're going to go through some of our code to see how we can make
コードを詳細に見ながらTensorFlowで
a Neural Network using the DNN class Regressor in TensorFlow.
DNNクラスのRegressorを使って NNを構築する方法を説明します
So here we are, we're going to learn how to use a Neural Network.
ここではNNの使用方法を学びます
So, we're going to use this housing data based on 1990 census data from California.
カリフォルニアの国勢調査に基づく 住宅データを使います
This data is at the city block level.
データは街区レベルなので
So, it's going to reflect features,
特徴を表します
the total number of rooms in that block,
その街区の総部屋数と
the total number of people who live in that block respectively.
その街区の総住居者数です
So, let's use a set of features to rate the house value.
この2つの特徴で住宅価値を評価しましょう
So, first let me set up.
まず設定します
So in the first cell, we're going to lower unnecessary libraries.
最初のセルで必要なライブラリをロードします
We're going to import the math,
math、shutil、numpy
shutil, numpy, pandas, tensorflow.
pandas, tensorflowをインポートします
Make sure your proposity is set to info so you can get a lots of results.
多数の結果を得るため verbosityをinfoにします
Make sure some reformatting for pandas is set.
pandasの再編成の設定を確認します
So, now we're going to load our dataset from this URL here,
ここでこのURLからデータセットを ロードします
or ml Carlifornia housing train data into a panda's data frame.
住宅トレーニングデータをpandaの データフレームに入れます
Next, we examine the data.
次はデータを精査します
So, it's a good idea to get to know your data a little bit before you work with it.
作業前に少しデータを見ておきます
We'll print out a quick summary of useful statistics on each column.
各列に統計値のまとめを出力します
This will include things like mean,
平均、標準偏差
standard deviation, max, min and various quantiles.
最大、最小、分位点などが含まれます
So first, what we're going to do is print off the head of the data frame.
まずデータフレームの見出しを出力します
What this does is simply print off an example of the first five rows of the dataset;
例としてデータセットの最初の5行のみを 出力します
longitude, latitude, housing median age,
緯度、経度、平均住宅築年数
total rooms, total bedrooms, population, households,
総部屋数、総寝室数、住居者数、世帯数
median income and median house value;
平均収入、平均住宅価値です
which is my label in this case.
これがここのラベルです
It's what I want to predict using these other features.
こうした特徴で予測することです
So, actually lets see what the statistics are.
では実際の予測値を見てみましょう
This I can do with df.describe.
df.describeの処理です
It will show me the count,
表示されるのはカウント
the means, standard deviation,
平均、標準偏差
the minimum, 25th percentile,
最小値、25パーセンタイル
the 50th percentile, the 75th percentile and the maximum.
50パーセンタイル、75パーセンタイル 最大値です
As you can see here, everything looks pretty clean here.
すべてがかなり単純に見えますが
However, it is on a city block level still.
ここはまだ街区レベルです
So, we're going to have to figure out how to do that on a per house level.
これを住宅レベルで行う方法を見つける必要が あります
So to do that, I take the number of rooms, if I want to find that,
これを行うには 部屋数を知りたい場合
I take the total rooms for the entire city block,
街区全体の総部屋数を
and divide with the total number of households in that block.
その街区の総世帯数で割ります
This will give me the average number of rooms per house.
これで住宅当たりの平均部屋数がわかります
Same goes for bedrooms,
寝室も同様です
I take the number of bedrooms,
寝室数を調べたら
I'm then going to use the total number of bedrooms in the whole block,
街区全体の総寝室数を
divide with the number of households in that block to get the average number of bedrooms.
その街区の世帯数で割って平均寝室数を求めます
Now, for persons per house,
住宅当たりの人数では
I'm going to take the total population
その街区の総住民数を
of that block and divide by the number of households,
世帯数で割ります
same with the average number of people in that house.
その住宅の平均居住者数と同じです
Now, if I do a df.describe,
df.describeを行うには
we'll see my original columns here.
ここの元の列を見ます
However, I have new columns added right here.
ただしここには新しい列を追加しています
This are my average number of rooms per house,
これは住宅当たりの平均部屋数
my average number of bedrooms per house,
住宅当たりの平均寝室数
and my average number of a persons per house.
住宅当たりの平均住居者数です
Excellent. Now, I can drop those population statistics now,
次はこれらの住居者統計値をドロップし
and say block level statistics;
街区レベルの統計値
like total rooms, total bedrooms,
総部屋数、総寝室数
population, households, and I'm going to drop all those columns in place.
居住者数、世帯数など すべての列を定位置にドロップします
So, I don't create a new data frame.
新データフレームはなし
And now, if I do df.describe,
df.describeでは
you'll see I have my new features over here,
新しい特徴はここにあります
my old features over there.
古い特徴はそこです
Here's my label, and those things I used before are no longer there.
これは今回のラベルです 以前使ったものはもうありません
This is now at a house level view.
これは住宅レベルのビューです
So now, let's build
ではNNモデルを構築して
All right. So, what we're going to do is create our feature columns.
ここで行うのは特徴列の作成です
So remember, feature columns are basically
特徴列は基本的に
getting our data into the right representation for our model to use.
使用するモデルの適切な表現にデータを入れます
So, even if it is already in floating point notation,
すでに浮動小数点表記になっていても
we still need to decide if it's going to be a floating point in a column or not.
列で浮動小数点になるかどうかを決定する 必要があります
So, it comes in here,
そしてここでは
and I'm looping as you can see here,
ご覧のようにループしています
over all the columns and median housing age,
すべての列と平均住宅築年数
median income, the number of rooms,
平均収入、部屋数
number of bedrooms, and the persons per house.
寝室数、住居者数です
After that, I want to do a little more feature engineering.
その後もう少し特徴エンジニアリングを行います
So, I'm going to create a new feature column called Longitude.
longitudeという 新しい特徴列を作ります
It's going to be a bucketized column of the numerical longitude,
数値の経度が入る bucketized_columnになり
with the spacing of linear space from a negative
間隔は線形空間
124.3 to negative 114.3 in steps of five.
-124.3～-114.3の5刻みになります
Then feature columns latitude,
次に特徴列latitudeでも
I'm going to have the same sort of thing,
同じことを行います
except now it's going to be from the latitudes 32.5 to 42 with 10 buckets in this.
ただしlatitudeの範囲は32.5～42で これに10のバケットが入ります
The reason I'm doing this is because California is longer than it is wider.
これを行っているのは カリフォルニアが縦長だからです
Therefore, our latitude should have a greater number of buckets;
そのためlatitudeの バケット数が多く
10 buckets versus the five buckets for longitude.
10バケットで longitudeは5バケット
Just printing out my feature column names.
特徴列の名前を出力します
Here, I can see, I have median income, persons per house,
ここに平均収入、住宅当たりの人数
number of rooms, housing median age,
部屋数、平均住居築年数
longitude, number of bedrooms and latitude.
経度、寝室数、緯度があります
That's great. But first,
いいですね しかしまず
we need to make sure we split this into a train and evaluation data set.
これをトレーニングと評価データセットに 分割します
So, that way I'm able to see how my model is progressing as I'm training.
これでトレーニングしながらモデルの進捗状況を 確認できます
To do this, I'm going to create a random mask,
そのためにランダムマスクを作成し
where I'm checking for the length of data frame,
データフレーム長をチェックします
I'm going to create that many number of random values,
多数のランダム値を
from a uniform distribution,
一様分布から作成し
and if they're less than 0.8,
値が0.8未満の場合は
I'm going to save it into this mask vector.
このマスクベクトルに保存します
What's going to happen is, this mask vector is actually length of the data frame,
このマスクベクトルがデータフレームの長さで
but they're all trues and false,
trueまたはfalseです
it is called a Boolean mask,
これをブールマスクと呼びます
when I apply this Boolean mask in my data frame.
ブールマスクをデータマスクに適用します
So therefore, for all things were that mask was true,
このマスクがtrueだった場合は
those rows will be put into trained data frame.
行がトレーニング済みデータフレームに入り
And for all values that are not true,
値がtrueでない場合は
that's what this tilde is right here,
波形記号がここにありますが
they will be put into evaluation data frame.
値は評価データフレームに入ります
Therefore, this will give me pretty much an 80 percent split into my train data frame,
これにより80%が トレーニングデータフレームに分割され
and the rest of the 20 percent of my data goes in the evaluation data frame.
残り20%のデータが評価データフレームに 入ります
Here, I also have a scale factor,
スケール因子もあります
as you can see, I'm 100,000.
ご覧のように100,000です
The reason for this is because I want to scale my labels here.
ここでラベルをスケーリングするためです
Because they are way too large.
ラベルが大きすぎます
As you can see, there are totally different scales.
まったく異なるスケールがあります
These are in the 100,000, millions range almost,
これらの範囲は10万やほぼ100万ですが
and these are all much smaller like single one or two digit floats.
これらはずっと小さく 浮動小数点数が1桁または2桁です
So, I'm going to do that.
ではそれを行います
I'm also going to create my batch size here,
バッチサイズも作成して
and set that, I'm going to set it to 100.
100に設定します
Set it to 100 rows at a time under each one of these data frames.
各データフレームで同時に100行に設定します
I had to then create my training input function.
トレーニング中の入力関数も 作成する必要があります
So for this, I'm going to use the nifty estimator pandas input function right here,
そこで適切なEstimator pandas入力関数を使用します
where X equals my features.
ここでxは特徴です
Well, this is going to create a dictionary of tensors,
これでテンソルの辞書を作成し
will be the output of that.
その出力になります
This will turn my train data frame of median house values of that column.
これがその列の平均住宅価値の トレーニングデータフレームを変換します
It'll read that into Y, which will then become a tensor for my labels.
これをyに読み込み これがラベルのテンソルになります
Number of epochs is going to equal one in
エポックの数は1になり
this case from a batch size and I am going to shuffle.
バッチサイズを基に シャッフルします
All right. Over here,
ここには
I have my eval input function.
評価の入力関数があります
Once again, it's going to use the pandas input function to do its work.
再度pandas入力関数を使って 処理を行います
And now, we're going to use all perimeter [inaudible] for the input data frame.
入力データフレームに [inaudible]を使います
However, I'm going to have shuffle,
shuffle = Falseにします
equal false because I don't want to shuffle
再現性が必要なので
my evaluations set because I want repeatability.
評価セットをシャッフルしません
I also create another function here called rmse,
ここでrmseという関数も作り
which is going to print out the rmse of my model.
モデルのRMSEを出力します
Calling in the name of it and calling the input function associated.
その名前を呼び出し 関連する入力関数を呼び出します
So for this, I'm going to create into the metrics.
ここでは測定基準を作成します
I'm going to model.evaluate of my estimator.
Estimatorのmodel.evaluateにします
Remember, my estimator is set as model.
Estimatorはモデルです
And I'm going to pass it to as input function,
これを入力関数として渡します
where it's going to be the input function that is passed to our print_rmse,
これが入力関数になり print_rmseに渡されます
and I'm going to do onestep.
これを1ステップで行います
The right news about this,
これに関する正しい情報は
is that I'm going to be- this metrics is out,
この測定基準がoutだということです
it should be dictionary.
dictionaryにします
It's still a regression problem.
回帰問題があります
So, I'm going to end up with loss,
そのため最後は損失
average loss, and a global step.
平均損失、グローバルステップになります
Then I'm going to print the rmse on this data set, and the answer will be,
次にこのデータセットのRMSEを出力し 答えは
I'm going to have to hit the square root
平方根が必要です
because currently the average loss is just the mse.
現在の平均損失はMSEです
From the rmse, I've check the square root.
RMSEから平方根をチェックし
Also you might notice that I'm multiplying by the scale here.
ここでスケールによる乗算を行っています
So, I can get back into the correct units of price, the mean the house value.
そのため正しい価格単位、平均住宅価値に 戻れます
Now, I'm going to equip my Linear Reggressor.
Linear Reggressorを準備します
I created an output directory,
出力ディレクトリです
this is where all my files will be saved from the training,
ここにトレーニングのファイルが保存されます
like my checkpoints, my event logs,
チェックポイントやイベントログ
any saved models for instance.
保存されたモデルなどです
I want remove it, to make sure I have a fresh start each time.
毎回新たに開始できるようこれを削除します
So, we're going to remove everything in that tree,
このツリーのすべてを削除し
make sure it's a clear fresh folder.
フォルダを空にします
I'm going to create my custom optimizer.
カスタムオプティマイザを作成します
This is Linear Regression. So, I'm going to
これが線形回帰です そこで
use a follow the regularized leader optimizer,
Follow the Regularized Leader オプティマイザを使用します
since that's usually a pretty good choice for that.
通常これが最適な選択です
I'm going to have a learning rate of 0.01,
学習率を0.01にして
then I'm going to create my model.
モデルを作成します
So here, I'm creating my estimator now.
Estimatorを作ります
It's going to be a linear aggressor,
Linear Regressorです
and I'm passing my model directory.
モデルディレクトリを渡します
So, I'm going to put my stuff,
必要なものを入れ
and then feature columns and I'm going to pass my feature columns values.
特徴列を入れて特徴列の値を渡します
So, these are the tensors for that.
これらはそのテンソルです
And then my optimizer is going to be my custom optimizer here [inaudible] leader.
オプティマイザはカスタムの Leaderです
I'm going to train for a number of steps here.
ここではトレーニングを ステップの数だけ行います
For this, I'm going to train for a hundred times
ここでのトレーニングは100回です
unlike to my data frame over my batch size.
データフレームとは異なります
Essentially, what this means, I may train for 100 epochs.
これはトレーニングを 100エポック行うという意味です
I then call model.train,
model.trainを呼び出し
passing my input function,
入力関数を渡します
specifically my training input function,
トレーニングの入力関数です
and my number of steps could be this number of steps I
ステップ数はここで作成したステップ数です
Then at the very end, I'm going to print the rmse of that model.
最後にモデルのRMSEを出力します
I'm going to call my evaluation input function,
評価の入力関数を呼び出します
so that way, it will be on my evaluation input functions set.
そのように評価の入力関数セットになります
As you can see, when I perform the training,
ご覧のようにトレーニングを行う場合
I have the default config here,
ここにデフォルトのconfigがあり
and changing that I create a checkpoint and I start the training process.
これを変更してチェックポイントを作成し トレーニングプロセスを開始します
I compute the loss at step one.
ステップ1で損失を計算
It looks like, and then that's how many steps per second I've done,
こうなります 次は1秒間に実施したステップ数
and as training proceeds,
トレーニングが進むと
the loss is hopefully going down.
損失は低下するはずです
We can see that my evaluation final average loss is 0.93,
ご覧のように評価の最終平均損失は0.93です
after 137 global steps,
グローバルステップは137
and my total loss is 3,141.
総損失は3,141です
And my evaluation, by multiplying back by the scale on my evaluations set,
評価は評価セットのスケールで乗算します
the rmse is $96,583.
RMSEは96,583ドルです
Remember, rmse is essentially the standard deviation of your residuals.
RMSEは本質的に残余の標準偏差です
Remember, in your residuals, are the difference
残余では
between your prediction and the actual label.
予測と実際のラベルに差があります
So now, let's see if we can do any better with my DNNRegressor.
次はDNNRegressorでの改善を 確認します
Everything is the same as before,
すべて前と同じですが
except this time I'm using the AdamOptimizer,
AdamOptimizerを使用します
because that's usually pretty great to use on DNNReggressor's rather than the [inaudible] leader.
[inaudible]リーダーより DNNReggressorに適しています
I'm also going to now change from the Linear Regressor to the DNNReggressor.
またLinearRegressorから DNNReggressorに変更します
Where I pass it as before everything else.
他はすべて前と同じように渡します
However, I'm going to add in my hidden units and I'm going to have one,
ただし隠れユニットを追加します
where the first layer has 100 hidden neurons.
隠れニューロンは最初の層には100
The second layer has 50 hidden neurons,
2番目の層には50
and the last layer has 20 hidden neurons.
最終層に20あります
I'm also passing the feature columns,
特徴列も渡します
the optimizer I created,
作成したオプティマイザ
which is using Adam this time.
今回はAdamを使います
Then a drop dropout of 10 percent.
ドロップアウトは10%です
Remember, this is the drafted probability and
これはドロップアウト確率で
not the key probability like it is in some other insulations.
キープ確率ではなく 他の分離にあります
I'm also creating the number of steps the same as before,
また前と同じくステップ数も作成します
and I'm training as before, and I printed my rmse.
前と同じくトレーニングし RMSEを出力しました
Let's see if it can do any better. All right.
改善されるか見てみましょう
So, it does everything the same as before,
既定のconfigのトレーニングでは
when my default configuration is at training.
すべてが前と同じように行われます
Let's see what the final steps are.
最終ステップでは
So, my average loss from my training is 0.67.
トレーニングの平均損失は0.67です
This is already a good sign because it's lower than what I had before, 0.93.
これはすでに良い兆候です 以前の0.93より低下しました
But on my rmse on this, it's $81,974.
しかしこれのRMSEは81,974ドルです
As you can see here, I have a lot smaller standard deviation compared to the last one,
標準偏差は前回と比べてかなり小さくなりました
which means this model is doing much better.
このモデルが改善されました
Of course, you can always make this much more
これをもっと複雑にして
complicated and use way more fancy algorithms,
もっと複雑なアルゴリズムも使えます
which goes to show you, that a Neural Network can very
つまりNNを使えば
easily get you much better performance than a Linear Regression can.
線形回帰より高い性能を簡単に得られるという ことです
Lastly, what we can do, we call this in TensorBoard,
最後にこれをTensorBoardで呼び出し
and we can look at how it's progressing.
その進捗状況を確認できます